[Music]
blessings everyone this is Chris kenel
from the rod vantage.com registered
holistic nutritionist raw food lifestyle
coach and raw Chef today we're going to
be making some freaking RW and falafal
quite possibly the best rawan flaf balls
out there you ready for it here we I
like it ra raage lik it ra baby I Like
It Raw yeah baby I Like It
Raw all right so let you know this
recipe is from my TR Retreat treats book
and if you want a free excerpt that has
not only this recipe but toui to ziki
and the falafel recipe itself then click
right here sign up for my newsletter and
you'll get that whole chapter for free
now let's look at the equipment we're
going to need for this so right now I
would recommend the Excalibur dehydrator
you need a dehydrator for this unless
you want to serve some soggy balls I
mean soggy Falafel balls you don't want
to serve soggy Falafel balls I like to
use a food processor to make the balls
if you do not have a food processor you
can also use a grater the recipe is
divided into two portions dry and wet
ingredients for the wet ingredients I
recommend the Vitamix blender it's an
amazing blender you can actually get one
right here with free shipping I highly
encourage you 7-year warranty best
blender in the business but those are
the things we need besides some
measuring cups maybe a spoon and your
hands to form the balls let's get into
the all right so this recipe actually
starts one or 2 days before you want to
serve it and not for a lot of it but
just for this we have a sixth cup of
chickpeas dried chickpeas you're going
to soak those in water for 12 hours and
then give them at least one rinse every
12 hours you can Sprout them as much as
you want so that will turn into this
much once they've been soaked and
sprouted for about 12 hours all right so
for the dry crumble portion ingredients
you will need4 cup raw walnuts dry or
fresh cilantro oregano and parsley to
taste two green onions a thir of a
cauliflower half a zucchini and one
medium carrot and then for the wet
ingredients you will need one half a
zucchini a small lemon4 red onion 1/4
cup pumpkin seeds don't forget the sprad
chickpeas and an optional 1/4 teaspoon
of cumin and garlic if you wanted a
little bit garlicky so I'm just going to
chop up some of these
ingredients just a nice rough chop and
throw them
in start with the hardier ingredients
carot and the cauliflower and we'll give
it a quick
[Music]
pulse so you got this beautiful pill
like consistency put it in a
bowl and then we'll add some
walnuts we'll add those to the
Bowl want to scrape out a little bit the
zucchini you can either grate or put in
the food processor if you're using in
the food processor You' got to be extra
careful cuz you don't want it just turn
into mush going to add the zucchini with
everything except for the white the
green
onion as well as
parsley cilantro and oregano to
taste let's check it out a little bit
more beautiful pour that into the bowl
scrape out this food processor cuz we're
done with it all right so we have this
beautiful dry or crumbled portion of the
recipe it's ready for us now we're going
to go into the wet portion of the recipe
so we have the zucchini chop it up throw
that into the trusty Vitamix we have the
lemon we'll squirt that in there W right
in the
eyeball try and avoid that if you can we
have the red onion as well as the
bottoms of the white onion if you don't
like onion you can omit it from the
recipe another trick is to finely chop
the green onion as well as the red onion
and let it sit for about a half an hour
that will dissipate the mustard oil and
make it a lot less irritating to your
digestive tract we'll put the sprouted
chickpeas in there the pumpkin seeds and
here we have the optional cumin and
garlic all right and now we're ready to
blend oh my God it smells so
[Applause]
good bless the Vitamix tamper all
[Music]
right mhm that's good all right get it
all in
there I'm so lazy I could use a
spatula all right maybe I'll use one I
want to get all of this stuff in here
this is like the cement to the flaff
ball mixture all right now all we have
to do is mix this up once it's all mixed
up take a bit into your hand just kind
of balce it around your hand carefully
handling the balls oh my God that's
disgusting sorry about that so you you
want these to be about pingpong or golf
ball sized put them up the front and
just keep rolling you don't want to
squeeze them too much then the juice
comes out and they become dry so you
just kind of form them all right so this
recipe makes between between 10 and 20
balls depending on how big you make them
These are nice golf ball size they'll
shrink down quite a bit we're going to
throw them in the Excalibur dehydrator
between 115 to 119 for 6 to 8
hours it's been about 4 and 1/2 5 hours
and you got to take the ones from the
front the Bottom's a little less done
this has already been flipped so take
ones from the front move them back these
ones up here so switch them around turn
them over
switch them around turn them
over put them back in until they're
fully crispy all the way around another
hour hour and a
half
ffos all right so the Falafel balls
should be done o they look pretty darn
perfect nice and crunchy smell delicious
let's go put them on some Falla so here
I got a nice cabbage leaf and I made a
little bit of hummus some hot sauce and
some taziki with some lettuce and
tomatoes normally I put some cucumbers
in there too but we'll just select a
couple balls and there you have it fulla
so if you like this recipe definitely
click here to sign up below for my
mailing list you'll get three free
ebooks plus Mediterranean nights so you
get the taziki the Tuli and a whole
bunch of other awesome recipes hope you
guys love
it ruffle
lles come on you know you want to try
these fluffa
balls
I ain't kidding yet seriously check
these two free ebooks lots of fun
recipes and quick and easy tips plus
check with this raw vegan ice cream
float recipe really
delicious excited to announce my new
iPhone app free with 101 freaking
rossome recipes teror Retreat treats
food combining charts shopping carts and
more